In music she found her dream, her love, herself.
Glitter is a drama, music, romance film directed by Vondie Curtis-Hall.
A young woman is catapulted into pop stardom, with her
already-famous DJ boyfriend calling the shots.
Billie Frank, played by Mariah Carey.
Julian 'Dice' Black, played by Max Beesley.
Louise, played by Da Brat.
Roxanne, played by Tia Texada.
Lillian Frank, played by Valarie Pettiford.
Kelly, played by Ann Magnuson.
Glitter is a 2001 American romantic musical drama film written by
Kate Lanier and directed by Vondie Curtis-Hall.
It stars Mariah Carey, Max Beesley, and Terrence Howard.
Carey plays Billie Frank, an aspiring singer who, along with her friends Louise
(rapper Da Brat) and Roxanne (Tia Texada), is a club dancer.
Music producer Timothy Walker (Howard) offers them a contract
as backup singers/dancers to another singer.
At the premiere of the song they record, Billie meets Julian "Dice" Black
(Beesley), a nightclub DJ who helps establish her solo career.
In the process, Billie and Dice fall in love.
Carey began working on a film and soundtrack project titled All That Glitters in 1997, but
it was put on hold in favor of other commitments with her record label.
Following this, she aimed to complete the film and
album project for the summer of 2001.
Shooting began in Toronto and New York City at the end of September 2000.
Carey used the time to work on the soundtrack of the film, along with
Eric Benét and Da Brat, who also appeared in the film.
The film and its accompanying soundtrack's release dates were delayed after Carey was suddenly
hospitalized, citing "extreme exhaustion" and a "physical and emotional breakdown".
The film was released on September 21, 2001 by 20th Century Fox in the United States and Canada and by Columbia TriStar Film
Distributors International in international markets, ten days after the release of the soundtrack on September 11, 2001.
Glitter was widely panned by critics and audiences and was a box-office bomb.
Reviewers were highly disappointed with the film, along with Carey's
performance, earning her a Golden Raspberry Award for worst actress.
This also caused the film to receive negative commentary on social media sites, with
Carey herself later admitting that she regretted being part of the film.
Some went on to call it one of the worst films ever made.
Glitter opened in 1,996 American theaters, and grossed $2.5 million in its first week,
with a worldwide total of $5.3 million against a $22 million budget.
The soundtrack of the film achieved moderate commercial success and went on to sell over two
million copies worldwide, considerably less than Carey's previous releases.
The film explores themes of talent, career woman, talent show, movie star.
The tone is emotional.